Finding Aid for the Letters to William Morris Colles, 1890-1926 LSC.2007
UCLA Library Special Collections
Letters to William Morris Colles
1890-1926
UCLA Library Special Collections
Colles, William Morris
LSC.2007
2 Linear Feet (4 boxes)
William Morris Colles (1855-1926) was a prominent literary agent in London, and a author. The collection consists of letters from various authors to Colles and his associates. Correspondents include Sir James Barrie, Arnold Bennett, E.F. Benson, Ford Madox Ford, Rider Haggard, and Somerset Maugham.
Restrictions on Access
Open for research. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
Provenance/Source of Acquisition
Winifred A. Myers, purchase, 1972.
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID: 999644843606533
Biography
Colles was born in 1855; he became a prominent literary agent in London; his published works include Literature and the pension list (1889) and Playright and copyright in all countries, showing how to protect a play or a book throughout the world (with Harold Hardy, 1906); he died in 1926.
Scope and Content
Collection consists of letters from various authors to literary agent William Morris Colles and his associates. Correspondents include Sir James Barrie, Arnold Bennett, E.F. Benson, Ford Madox Ford, Rider Haggard, and Somerset Maugham.
Organization and Arrangement
Arranged in the following series:
A - B (Box 1).
C - G (Box 2).
H - O (Box 3).
P - Z (Box 4).
Literary agents -- England -- London -- Correspondence.; Colles, William Morris, 1855-1926--Archives.
- A - B
  - A. Beckett, Arthur William, 1844-1909., (2 items) (Box 1)
  - Allingham, Helen (Paterson), 1848-1926., (2 items) (Box 1)
  - Archer, William, 1856-1924., (4 items) (Box 1)
  - Arnold, Sir Edwin, 1832-1904., (38 items) (Box 1)
  - Baring-Gould, Sabine, 1834-1924., (1 item) (Box 1)
  - Barnett, Edith A., (20 items) (Box 1)
  - Barr, Robert, 1850-1912., (12 items) (Box 1)
  - Barrie, Sir James Matthew, bart., 1860-1937., (1 item) (Box 1)
  - Bayly, Ada Ellen, 1857-1903., (8 items) (Box 1)
  - Bennett, Arnold, 1867-1931., (4 items) (Box 1)
  - Benson, Edward Frederic, 1867-1940 (Box 1, Folder 1-18)
    - 1897., (1 item) (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - 1899., (20 items) (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - 1900., (8 items) (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - 1901., (31 items) (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - 1904., (1 item) (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - 1905., (2 items) (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - 1907., (6 items) (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - 1908., (1 item) (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - 1909., (27 items) (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - 1910., (21 items) (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - 1911., (31 items) (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - 1912., (4 items) (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - 1913., (3 items) (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - 1914., (1 item) (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - 1915., (1 item) (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - 1916., (11 items) (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - 1919., (6 items) (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - 1921., (8 items) (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Besant, Walter, 1836-1901., (2 items) (Box 1)
  - Birkerstaffe, Francis Browning Drew, count, 1853-1928., (15 items) (Box 1)
  - Black, William, 1841-1893., (1 item) (Box 1)
  - Blackwood, William, 1836-1912., (12 items) (Box 1)
  - Bland, Edith (Nesbit), 1858-1924., (3 items) (Box 1)
  - Blatchford, Robert, 1851-1943., (5 item) (Box 1)
  - Burgin, George Brown, 1856-1944., (1 item) (Box 1)
- C - G
  - Caine, William Ralph Hall, 1865-1939., (1 item) (Box 2)
  - Cannan, Gilbert, b.1884., (1 item) (Box 2)
  - Canton, William, 1845-1926., (23 items) (Box 2)
  - Childers, Hugh Robert Eardley, 1862-1912., (13 items) (Box 2)
  - Clifford, Lucy (Lane) "Mrs. W.K. Clifford" d. 1929., (16 items) (Box 2)
  - Coleridge, Gilbert James Duke, b.1859., (3 items) (Box 2)
  - Conyers, Mrs. Dorothea (Smyth), b.1873., (2 items) (Box 2)
  - Courtney, William Leonard, 1850-1928., (18 items) (Box 2)
  - Crawford, Oswald John Frederic, 1839-1909., (64 items) (Box 2)
  - Croker, Bithia Mary (Sheppard) d. 1920., (1 item) (Box 2)
  - Curzon, George Nathaniel Curzon, 1st marquis, 1859-1925., (4 items) (Box 2)
  - Daily Mail, London., (1 item) (Box 2)
  - Davidson, Hugh Coleman, b.1852., (37 items) (Box 2)
  - Dobson, Austin, 1840-1921., (1 item) (Box 2)
  - Edge, John Henry., (13 items) (Box 2)
  - Emanuel, Walter Lewis, 1869-1915., (1 items) (Box 2)
  - Field, Julian Osgood, 1849-1925., (52 items) (Box 2)
  - Findlater, Jane Helen, 1866-1946., (16 items) (Box 2)
  - Findlater, Mary, 1865-1963., (12 items) (Box 2)
  - Findlater, Mora., (1 item) (Box 2)
  - Finnemore, John, b.1863., (1 item) (Box 2)
  - Fitzgerald, Percy Hetherington, 1834-1925., (7 items) (Box 2)
  - Fletcher, Josepy Smith, 1863-1935., (38 items) (Box 2)
  - Ford, Ford Madox, 1873-1939., (1 item) (Box 2)
  - Fowler, Sir Montague, bart., 1858-1933., (4 items) (Box 2)
  - Freshfield, Douglas William, 1845-1934., (1 item) (Box 2)
  - Furniss, Harry, 1854-1925., (1 item) (Box 2)
  - Garvice, Charles, d.1920., (2 items) (Box 2)
  - Gilchrist, Robert Murray, 1868-1917., (11 items) (Box 2)
  - Gissing, Algernon, b.1860., (1 item) (Box 2)
  - Gosse, Edmund Wilson, 1849-1929., (1 item) (Box 2)
  - Graham, Harry, 1874-1936., (10 items) (Box 2)
  - Graham, James M., (40 items) (Box 2)
  - Grand, Sarah (pseudonym), 1862-1943., (5 items) (Box 2)
  - The Graphic, London., (1 item) (Box 2)
  - Graves, Alfred Perceval, 1846-1931., (2 items) (Box 2)
  - Gribble, Francis Henry, 1862-1946., (4 items) (Box 2)
  - Griffith, Arthur, 1872-1922., (1 item) (Box 2)
- H - O
  - Haggard, Sir Henry Rider, 1856-1925., (2 items) (Box 3)
  - Hall, Harold Fielding, 1859-1917., (8 items) (Box 3)
  - Harraden, Beatrice, 1864-1936., (3 items) (Box 3)
  - Hatton, Joseph, 1841-1907., (1 item) (Box 3)
  - Hawley, G., (11 items) (Box 3)
  - Heinemann, William., (1 item) (Box 3)
  - Henderson, Myra., (39 items) (Box 3)
  - Hewlett, Maurice Henry, 1861-1923., (12 items) (Box 3)
  - Hicks, Beatrice M., (6 items) (Box 3)
  - Hyne, Charles John Cutcliffe Wright, b.1866., (4 items) (Box 3)
  - James, Mrs. Florence Glice (Price), 1857-1929., (104 items) (Box 3)
  - Jepson, Edgar, b.1864., (1 item) (Box 3)
  - Keiley, Jarvis., (7 items) (Box 3)
  - Kennard, Mary E., (59 items) (Box 3)
  - Kennedy, H.A., (3 items) (Box 3)
  - Kernahan, Coulson, b.1858., (1 item) (Box 3)
  - Kropotkin, Petr Aleksieevich, kniaz, 1842-1921., (1 item) (Box 3)
  - Lean, Florence (Marryat) Church, 1837-1899., (3 items) (Box 3)
  - Lely, John Mounteney, 1839-1907., (29 items) (Box 3)
  - Lowndes, Marie Adelaide (Belloc), 1868-1947., (1 item) (Box 3)
  - Lowry, Henry Dawson, 1869-1906., (14 items) (Box 3)
  - Lynch, Harry Finnis Blosse, 1862-1913., (1 item) (Box 3)
  - McCarthy, Justin Huntly, 1860-1936., (1 item) (Box 3)
  - MacFall, Haldane, 1860-1928., (1 item) (Box 3)
  - Macnaughtan, Sarah Broom, d.1916., (1 item) (Box 3)
  - Mason, Alfred Edward Woodley, 1865-1948., (1 item) (Box 3)
  - Matthews, Brander, 1852-1929., (1 item) (Box 3)
  - Maugham, William Somerset, 1874-1965., (5 items) (Box 3)
  - Maxse, Leopold James, 1864-1932., (1 item) (Box 3)
  - Maxwell, Sir Herbert Eustace, 7th baronet, b.1845., (1 item) (Box 3)
  - Merrick, Leonard, 1864-1939., (2 items) (Box 3)
  - Miles, Eustace Hamilton, b.1868., (1 item) (Box 3)
  - Miller, Ester., (1 item) (Box 3)
  - Molesworth, Mary Louise (Stewart), 1842-1921., (12 items) (Box 3)
  - Muddock, Joyce Emerson Preston, b.1843., (16 items) (Box 3)
  - Neufeld, Charles, 1856-1918., (6 items) (Box 3)
  - Norris, William Edward, 1847-1925., (1 item) (Box 3)
  - Northcliffe, Alfred Charles William Harmsworth, 1st viscount, 1865-1922., (7 items) (Box 3)
  - O'Grady, Standish, 1846-1928., (2 items) (Box 3)
  - Ollivant, Alfred, 1874-1927., (12 items) (Box 3)
  - O'Neill, John., (7 items) (Box 3)
  - Orr, Alexander B., (57 items) (Box 3)
  - Osbourne, Lloyd, 1868-1947., (7 items) (Box 3)
  - Oswell, William Edward., (1 item) (Box 3)
  - Oxenham, John (pseudonym), 1852-1941., (10 items) (Box 3)
- P - Z
  - Pall Mall Magazine., (1 item) (Box 4)
  - Parker, Sir Gilbert, bart., 1862-1932., (6 items) (Box 4)
  - Parker, Joseph, 1830-1902., (1 item) (Box 4)
  - Partridge, Sir Bernard, 1861-1945., (1 item) (Box 4)
  - Paterson, Arthur Henry, 1862-1928., (1 item) (Box 4)
  - Payn, James, 1830-1898., (22 items) (Box 4)
  - Pemberton, Sir Max, 1863-1950., (11 items) (Box 4)
  - Pendleton, John., (2 items) (Box 4)
  - Pollock, Walter Harries, 1850-1926., (13 items) (Box 4)
  - Pryce, Richard, 1864-1942., (1 item) (Box 4)
  - Quiller-Conch, Sir Arthur Thomas, 1863-1944., (1 item) (Box 4)
  - Reeve, Henry Fenwick, 1854-1920., (11 items) (Box 4)
  - Rhys, Ernest, 1859-1946., (12 items) (Box 4)
  - Rideing, William Henry, 1853-1918., (12 items) (Box 4)
  - Roberts, Morley, b.1857., (36 items) (Box 4)
  - Seaman, Sir Owen, 1861-1936., (1 item) (Box 4)
  - Shelley, Henry Charles., (2 items) (Box 4)
  - Shepperson, Claude Allin., (2 items) (Box 4)
  - Shorter, Clement King, 1857-1926., (26 items) (Box 4)
  - Sidgwick, Cecily (Ullmann), d.1934., (1 item) (Box 4)
  - Sladen, Douglas Brooke Wheelton, 1856-1947., (6 items) (Box 4)
  - Smith, Elizabeth Thomasina (Meade), d.1914., (19 items) (Box 4)
  - Spender, John Alfred, 1862-1942., (1 item) (Box 4)
  - Steel, Mrs. Flora Annie (Webster), 1847-1929., (8 items) (Box 4)
  - Stewart, John Alexander, 1846-1933., (3 items) (Box 4)
  - Straight, Sir Douglas., (2 items) (Box 4)
  - Stodard-Walker, Archibald., (14 items) (Box 4)
  - Sutcliffe, Halliwell, b.1870., (4 items) (Box 4)
  - Swan, Myra., (1 item) (Box 4)
  - Tanqueray, Mrs. Bertram., (17 items) (Box 4)
  - Teague, John Jessop, 1856-1929., (10 items) (Box 4)
  - Temple Bar., (1 item) (Box 4)
  - Tirebuck, William Edward, 1854-1900., (23 items) (Box 4)
  - Tweedie, Ethel Brilliana (Harley) d. 1940., (3 items) (Box 4)
  - Upward, Allen, 1863-1926 (Box 4, Folder 1-2)
    - 1895-1900., (63 items) (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - 1901-1922., (55 items) (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Vallings, Harold., (34 items) (Box 4)
  - Ward, Mary Augusta (Arnold), 1851-1920., (2 items) (Box 4)
  - Watson, Henry Brereton Marriott, 1863-1921., (1 item) (Box 4)
  - Williamson, C.M., (4 items) (Box 4)
  - Yeats-Brown, Francis Charles Claypon, b.1886., (1 item) (Box 4)
  - Zangwill, Israel, 1864-1926., (25 items) (Box 4)
  - Zimmern, Helen, 1846-1934., (3 items) (Box 4)
  - Unidentified., (6 items) (Box 4)